Rowan Carmichael

Frontend Engineer

carmichaelr@hotmail.co.uk

in linkedin.com/in/rowan-carmichael

+64210794594

Relocating to Melbourne, Australia

in linkedin.com/in/rowan-carmichael

github.com/RowanCarmichael

rowancarmichael.github.io/site

Skilled frontend engineer with a passion for creating innovative React applications. A confident communicator and critical thinker with an inquisitive personality who always keeps the best usability experience in mind. Thoroughly enjoys the challenge of solving new problems and is motivated above all else to learn and grow.

SKILLS

Experienced In: Familiar With:

ReactJS SQL
JavaScript (ES6+) Java
HTML5 C#
CSS3 / LESS / Sass Xamarin

FAVOURITE FRAMEWORKS

CSS Modules Eslint Redux Mobx Chai Enzyme Mocha Selenium Node.js (Express) Flow Babel Webpack Yarn Npm Git Storybook

WORK EXPERIENCE

React Frontend Engineer

EROAD Limited February 2016 – Ongoing

Tasked with leading, co-developing and maintaining the frontend for five new SaaS projects related to driver health & safety, reports/auditing, and vehicle maintenance/compliance. All within a continuous delivery environment

After completing the first major React project in the mobile team; personally received the EROAD 2017 CEO Award and helped the team achieve the EROAD Q1 2017 and the Q4 2017 Engineering Team Awards

Taught/mentored four developers learning React and organised several workshop presentations defining development best-practices and standards for React frontend across the company

Created and maintained unit, component, UI and end-to-end level tests for all frontend code I wrote which helped our team consistently have the lowest bug rate out of all product-based development teams in the company

Worked closely with backend developers, UI/UX designers, product managers and testers in an agile development environment utilising both Scrum and Kanban methodologies. Includes time as a Scrum (Kanban) master

Web Developer

Opus International Consultants Limited

March 2015 - November 2015

Worked part-time in a team of three developers, creating a real-time mobile web app hazard management system as a university industry project

Computer Science Lab Demonstrator

University of Auckland Computer Science Department

March 2015 - November 2015

Assisted undergraduate students with computer science related questions for practical assignments and tutorials

EDUCATION

BTech(Hons) Specialising in Information Technology

University of Auckland

March 2012 - November 2015

HOBBIES / INTERESTS

I strive for a lifestyle of balanced mental and physical wellbeing. I do my best to keep active playing competitive ultimate frisbee (up to the national level), yoga, gymming and walking wherever I can. To relax and unwind I like to play piano, cook, and I am an avid gamer (both PC and board/card games - my favourite being strategy games)